greatrun.org 2017-12-17

# Greatrun.org website privacy and cookies policies

###  Introduction

1.1 For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 the Websites are owned and operated by Nova International Limited.

1.2 The privacy and security of the users of the Websites is important to us. This privacy policy explains how we use the information we collect about you, how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information, and the procedures that we have in place to safeguard your privacy.

1.3 Our privacy policy relates only to information that we obtain from you. If you visit a website operated by a third party through a link included on the Websites, your information might be used differently by the operator of the linked website.

Back to the top

###  The Information we collect and how we use it

2.1 The type of information we may collect about you includes:   
2.1.1 your name and address;   
2.1.2 your phone number and e-mail address;   
2.1.3 details about the services you specifically request;   
2.1.4 your gender and date of birth;   
2.1.5 whether or not you have a medical condition (although we do not usually ask what type of condition);   
2.1.6 whether or not you are a wheelchair user;   
2.1.7 a username and password for your online account; and   
2.1.8 a security question and answer for your online account;   
2.1.9 whether or not you are a Bupa member;   
2.1.10 If you have entered a child/minor into our events we will hold details about the child/minor as well as the parent/guardian. 

2.2 We will not collect or store any other sensitive information about you without your explicit consent.

2.3 The information you provide to us when using the Websites will be processed for the following reasons:   
2.3.1 to administer your user account with us;   
2.3.2 to process any request for advice or information supplied by us;   
2.3.3 to send you health and safety and other relevant event information for any Great Run event that you are participating in;   
2.3.4 to notify you of event, activities, publication and services that may be of interest to you should you consent to receiving these from us; and   
2.3.5 to comply with our statutory and regulatory obligations. 

2.4 Any information that we collect about you is stored electronically on our database. It may also be printed and stored in our filing system. We may also provide copies of your information to our subcontractors or charities. We would also like to provide your information to carefully selected third parties for the purposes of information and publicity. If you do not wish us to disclose your information we offer an opt out box which should be ticked on the registration form.

2.5 We would like to contact you in the future for marketing purposes by post and e-mail. If you don’t want to be contacted we provide you the facility of using an opt out box to tell us on the entry registration form or there is an additional opt out whenever an email is sent. The unsubscribe service can also be found at [ http://www.greatrun.org/edm/administration/unsubscribe/](http://www.greatrun.org/edm/administration/unsubscribe/)

Back to the top

###  Our use of cookies and other information gathering technologies

**3.1 About Cookies**

3.1.1 Cookies are small (4Kb) text files that are placed on your computer or device by websites that you visit. Cookies allow a website to ‘remember’ you either for the duration of your visit – session cookies – or between visits – persistent cookies. Cookies, therefore, can expire at the end of session or can persist for days, months or even years. The persistence of a cookie is under the control of the website that sets it.

3.1.2 Cookies can be used for many purposes but typically are used to remember who you are between pages on a website or for storing your preferences and generally improving your experience of a website.

3.1.3 Cookies can be set by the website you are visiting – first party cookies – or by other websites that are using another website to host content – third-party cookies. If a website embedded, say, a YouTube video, YouTube may well set a cookie when the video is viewed, this would be a ‘third-party’ cookie.

**3.2 Managing cookies**

3.2.1 Most web browsers allow at least a degree of control over cookies through their settings. You can opt to receive an alert whenever a cookie is set or even to disallow the setting of cookies altogether. You can also delete all existing cookies. 

3.2.2 For information about how to manage or delete cookies for you particular browser, please refer to the browser’s documentation, Alternatively, you can visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/), which has comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of desktop browsers. 

3.2.3 Note, many websites use Adobe Flash Player to deliver video content to their users. Adobe utilise their own cookies, which are not manageable through your browser settings. The cookies are used by the Flash Player for various purposes, such as storing preferences or tracking users.

**3.3 Use of Cookies on the Great Run Website**

3.3.1 Recent legislation (The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended in 2011) requires websites based in the EU to:

  * Inform visitors about the purpose of cookies that the website sets
  * Obtain consent before setting cookies

**3.4 The Purpose of Great Run Cookies**

3.4.1 In accordance with the legislation, the table below lists the cookies that are set on the Great Run website.

Back to the top

###  Cookies

**Name**

| 

**Expiry**

| 

**Details**

| 

**Third-party**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
GreatRunLinkCookie

| 

1 Day

| 

Tracking cookie used within emails and photo pages

|  | 

Used to track the number of event registrations originating from a defined marketing source. The information provided allows us to tailor the content and target our communications more effectively.  
  
.GRASPXAUTH

| 

Session

| 

Authentication Token for Login area

|  | 

This cookie is essential for the operation of the website  
  
ASP.Net_SessionId

| 

Session

| 

Issued by ASP.NET. Contains the user's session ID

|  | 

This cookie is essential for the operation of the website. Visit Microsoft’s website for detailed information - <http://support.microsoft.com/kb/899918>  
  
pysid

| 

1 Day

| 

Session ID for a user

| 

Marathon Photos

| 

Used to store a customer's order. Allows a customer to visit the site, close their browser and then return (within 24 hours) and continue their order. Visit Marathon Photos’ website for details of their privacy policy - [http://www.marathon-photos.com](http://www.marathon-photos.com/)  
  
lang

| 

Permanent

| 

Preferred language for the user

| 

Marathon Photos

| 

Allows a visitor to permanently override our browser language detection code to suit their preference. The cookie avoids the need for visitors to set their preferred language each time the site is visited if it conflicts with the default language of their browser. Visit Marathon Photos’ website for details of their privacy policy - [http://www.marathon-photos.com](http://www.marathon-photos.com/)  
  
magazine_cover

| 

1 Day

| 

Personalized Magazine Cover data.

| 

Marathon Photos

| 

Visit Marathon Photos’ website for details of their privacy policy - [http://www.marathon-photos.com](http://www.marathon-photos.com/)  
  
event

| 

1 Day

| 

Personalized Magazine Event Name.

| 

Marathon Photos

| 

Visit Marathon Photos’ website for details of their privacy policy - [http://www.marathon-photos.com](http://www.marathon-photos.com/)  
  
bib

| 

1 Day

| 

Personalized Magazine Bib

| 

Marathon Photos

| 

Visit Marathon Photos’ website for details of their privacy policy - [http://www.marathon-photos.com](http://www.marathon-photos.com/)  
  
_utma

| 

2 years

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
_utmb

| 

30 mins

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
_utmc

| 

Session

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
_utmz

| 

6 months

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
_ga

| 

2 years

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
_gat

| 

10 minutes

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Google

| 

Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. Visit Google's website for details of their privacy policy - <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>  
  
Back to the top

###  Obtaining Consent

**3.5 Obtaining Consent**

3.5.1 For visitors to the website, at the top of the home page there is a notice alerting the visitor to the use of cookies on the Great Run website. The notice gives the option to accept the use of cookies on the Great Run website.

3.5.2 By choosing to accept their use, a cookie is placed on the visitor’s computer so that the Great Run website can ‘remember’ the visitor’s preference. On subsequent visits to the website, if the presence of the cookie is detected the notice will not appear.

3.5.3 Note, it is not technically possible to transfer this preference so you will see the notice again if you browse the Great Run website on other devices or browsers.

3.5.4 From time to time we will be setting new cookies as we add features to the Great Run website. These cookies will be listed in the table above and we recommend you regularly view the Privacy and Cookie Policy for any changes.

3.5.5 If you opt not to accept cookies but wish to visit the Great Run website you will need to manage the cookies using the settings on your browser, as discussed in the section above. However, if you browse the Great Run website having opted to disallow cookies you will still be able to use the website but certain features and functionality will be lost.

3.5.6 If you choose to ignore the notice but continue using the website, depending on the settings on your browser, cookies will be set. If you are at all concerned about cookies, we recommend that you do not use the Great Run website until you have clearly understood the implications or have altered your browser settings accordingly.

Back to the top

###  How we protect your information

4.1 We will keep your personal information confidential except to the extent that we are compelled to disclose it by law (for example where fraud or other crime is involved) or to comply with an instruction of a regulatory body of competent jurisdiction. To comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 we follow strict security procedures for storing data.

4.2 The personal information that we hold will be held securely to ensure no unauthorised disclosure or access. The internet is not a secure medium. We have put in place various security measures but you are advised to treat the internet as an insecure medium in all of your communications with us.

Back to the top

###  Updating Your Details

If any of the information that you have provided to us when you enter an event changes, for example if you change your email address, please update your Profile section on the greatrun.org website.

Back to the top

###  Your Consent

6.1 By submitting your information to us on the account registration form, you consent to the use of that information as set out in this policy. If we change this privacy policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the Websites, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it at all times. We may also email you should we make any changes so that you may consent to our use of your information in that way. Continued use of our Websites will signify that you agree to any such changes.

6.2 Owing to the global nature of the internet's infrastructure the information you provide may be temporarily transferred to and stored in countries outside the European Economic Area, for example if the location of the Internet service provider hosting our Websites is outside of this area. By agreeing to our terms and conditions of use of our Websites you consent to any transfer of your personal information outside the European Economic Area.

Back to the top

###  General

7.1 Should you wish to obtain a copy of the personal data that we hold on you, please send an e-mail to [info@greatrun.org](mailto:info@greatrun.org). As soon as we are satisfied as to your identity, we will send to you a copy of all the data that we hold concerning you.

7.2 If you have a complaint regarding any breach of this privacy policy, please contact us at [info@greatrun.org](mailto:info@greatrun.org). When we receive the complaint, we will review it and ensure that we are in compliance with our privacy policy and all applicable laws. We will contact you to inform you of the results of our review of your complaint.

Back to the top

###  Merchant of record

Nova International Limited is a company registered in England and Wales (company number 3300783). Great Run is a trading name of Nova International Limited. Nova International Ltd is the merchant of record selling entries in Great Run events.

Back to the top
